thebreakfastproject.com 2014-11-25

# Privacy Policy - Milk Life

This site (“Milk”) has a policy to respect and protect the privacy of its users. This privacy policy statement tells you how we collect information from you and how we use it. Using the Internet should be a fun experience and we want to help you make it so.

Milk occasionally collects and stores personal user information in connection with promotions at [www.milklife.com](http://www.milklife.com/). Whenever information of that kind is collected, Milk checks the ages of all site visitors before accepting information from them. No information is collected from guests under the age of 13 unless parental permission to do so is obtained as described below in the section designated “POLICY FOR KIDS (INDIVIDUALS UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE).”

From time to time, Milk requests personal information such as your name, e-mail address and birth date. For example, we may request personal information when you request brochures or information on diet and exercise, or when you register to enter a promotion such as a sweepstakes or contest. Whenever Milk collects and stores such personal user information, information you provide will not be disclosed to third parties without your consent; however, Milk may share aggregate information about our visitors (for example, what percentages of our visitors are male and female) with advertisers, business partners, sponsors, and other third parties in order to customize the content of our site to deliver a better experience for our visitors.

Whether Milk collects personal information for complying with your requests or in connection with your participation in a promotion or for purposes of verifying your compliance with Milk policies and federal, state, and local laws, and/or for editorial and feedback solicitation purposes, we will collect only such information as is necessary for those purposes and nothing more. We will not collect any information from children under 13 that is not necessary for participation in promotions such as sweepstakes or contests or fulfillment of requests for information, prizes or premium items. As more fully described below under the heading “POLICY FOR KIDS,” we will not use personal information collected from children under 13 for any purpose except for its intended use, which shall be disclosed at the time such information is requested.

Milk may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) Milk’s rights or property, other Milk users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. Milk may also disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it.

**OPTING OUT**  
Information provided at the time of registration or submission from a guest who is 13 years of age or over may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by Milk. To keep you in control of your personal information and the communications directed to you, you may opt out of receiving communications from Milk about new features or services. If you object to such use for any reason, you may stop that use by e-mail request to [milk@webershandwick.com](mailto:milk@webershandwick.com).

**POLICY FOR KIDS (INDIVIDUALS UNDER 13 YEARS OF AGE)**  
Milk encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the sites. No information should be submitted to or posted at Milk by guests under 13 years of age without the consent of their parent or guardian. If Milk collects any personal information from children under 13 (and only after obtaining parental permission to do so), Milk will collect only such information as is necessary for the intended purpose. Milk will not provide any personally identifying information whatsoever from our guests under 13 years of age to any third party for any purpose without consent of a parent or guardian. In addition, Milk will provide a secure Web page that allows parents to view, revise and/or delete all information gathered about their children; to consent to Milk’s collection and use of such information; and to consent to disclosure of such information to third parties. Links to that page will be prominently displayed on the milklife.com homepage, within this Privacy Policy, on all pages where information is gathered on the site, and in emails sent to parents to confirm permission to collect user data.

Guests under 13 years of age may participate in activities on our site upon registration (such as entry in a sweepstakes), unless a parent or guardian invalidates their registration. When a guest under 13 registers for a sweepstakes or contest, he/she will be required either to: (a) provide the e-mail address of a parent or guardian who will then receive an e-mail alert regarding his/her child’s attempted registration, or (b) print the registration/entry form and mail it with a parent/guardian’s signature. If such a guest wins, notification and prizes will be sent to the parent or guardian. Publication of names, ages, or likenesses of promotion winners under 13 requires parental or guardian consent.

Unsolicited requests for information on a one-time basis will be honored without parental consent, and any personal information used for purposes of responding will not be retained or used for any other purpose.

**POLICY FOR TEENS (INDIVIDUALS 13 TO 17 YEARS OF AGE)**  
Guests who are 13 to 17 years of age should seek parental consent before providing any personal identifying information on our site.

**USE OF IP ADDRESSES**  
An IP address is a number that’s automatically assigned to your computer whenever you’re surfing the Web. Web servers — the big computers that “serve up” Web pages — automatically identify your computer by its IP address. Milk collects IP addresses for the purposes of system registration, to report aggregate information to our promotional partners, and to audit the use of our site.

When guests request pages from Milk sites, our servers log the guests’ IP addresses. We do not normally link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that a user’s session will be logged, but the user remains anonymous to us. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our house rules or terms of service or to protect our service, site, customers, or others.

**USE OF COOKIES**  
The milklife.com site uses cookie and tracking technology. Cookie and tracking technology is useful for gathering information such as browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to the web site, and understanding how visitors use the site. Cookies can also help tailor the site to visitors’ needs and help customize the site for visitors. For example, we may use cookies to make sure you don’t see the same information repeatedly. Also, if you have elected to store your favorite recipes or activities at the site, cookies help us do this. The site may also use cookies to deliver content specific to your interests and for other similar purposes. We use general IP address information to better understand how the site is utilized. Personal information cannot be collected via cookies and other tracking technology, however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information. Aggregate (not individual), cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties.

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**  
Users should be aware that when they are on Milk, they can be directed to other sites, the content and practices of which are beyond our control. There are links to other sites from Milk pages that take you outside our service. This includes links from partners that may use Milk or the Milk’s logo as part of a co-branding agreement.

These other sites may send their own cookies to users, collect data, or solicit personal information. Please keep in mind that whenever you give out personal information online that information can be collected and used by people you don’t know. While Milk strives to protect their users’ personal information and privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you disclose online and you do so at your own risk.

Milk’s policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond Milk’s control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation.

**SECURITY**  
The importance of security for all personally identifiable information associated with our guests is of utmost concern to us. We exercise great care in providing secure transmission of your information from your PC to our servers. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Milk can’t ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**UNSOLICITED MATERIALS**  
Please note that it is our policy not to accept or consider unsolicited creative, production-related or other materials of any kind. We appreciate your cooperation in adhering to this policy.

**DISCLAIMERS AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY**  
We make no representations or warranties of any kind as to: (a) the accuracy or completeness of the information or materials on the site and assume no responsibility for any errors or omissions in its content; (b) the availability for use of any copyrighted, trademarked or proprietary materials of third parties that may appear in this site; (c) computer viruses or other bugs that third parties may embed in or attach to this site without our knowledge or consent; (d) any software made available for downloading, copying or other use through this site; or (e) the merchantability, fitness for use, title and/or non-infringement of any or all of the contents of this site.

Neither we nor anyone involved in the creation or delivery of this site or whose materials or information appear on this site shall have any liability (whether based on contract, tort, statute or otherwise) for any costs, losses, damages (whether direct, indirect, compensatory, special, lost profits, liquidated, consequential or punitive), arising out of or in connection with the your access to, browsing of or use of this site or any of the contents of this site.

**COPYRIGHT AND TRADEMARK NOTIC** E  
This site is protected by U.S. copyright laws, and may be protected by the copyright laws of other countries and jurisdictions. Except as specifically permitted below, any copy, reproduction, display, performance or retransmission of the contents of this site is strictly prohibited.

Any use of "Milk LIfe®," "milklife.com," “The Breakfast Project," “milkmustache.com,” “Got Milk?®” and any other trademarks, trade names and logos in which we, our subsidiaries, affiliates, divisions and licensors do business is strictly prohibited absent our prior written consent. In addition, the names, trade names and trademarks of third parties, including our promotional partners, that appear on this site are proprietary to their respective owners and may be used only with their express written permission. The mark and logo for "Milk LIfe®," and “got milk?®” are registered trademarks of the California Fluid Milk Processor Advisory Board.

**USE OF MILK MATERIALS**  
All of our proprietary documents, images, designs and information, including information about our businesses and other public information posted about our company on this site may be copied, reproduced, downloaded and used, provided that: (1) copyright notice in the form “© The National Milk Processor Promotion Board”. Used With Permission. All rights reserved.” appears on every copy or reproduction of such materials; (2) you only use these materials for non-commercial, personal purposes; (3) you do not alter, edit or condense these materials; and (4) you do not use these materials to ridicule, disparage, harass or annoy anyone.

If you would like to use, copy, upload or retransmit any of our proprietary materials, call or e-mail us to request written permission. The contents of this site may contain documents, images, information and other materials not proprietary to us, such as photographs, clip art, film clips, musical passages, audio track or sound effects elements, or the names, trade names, trademarks, logos or designations of third parties. Any use whatsoever of any these non-Milk Materials is strictly prohibited, unless the prior written permission of the appropriate third parties has been secured.

**User-Generated Content Policy**

**1.     ** **Overview**

We respect third-party content and the members of our communities, and recognize the importance of providing credit for ideas, images, and written content. User-generated content provides opportunities for brands to connect with  _bloggers, celebrities, and social media communities_  in exciting and dynamic ways. They also can present potential public relations, privacy, legal and other concerns. For that reason, MilkPEP has developed these Rules of Engagement to provide general guidance on common issues faced in the social media space. Our content policy applies to all content posted to MilkPEP social channels in the public domain.

The laws that govern user-generated content media are complex and are continuing to evolve in response to fast-paced changes in technology. In certain respects, these rules of engagement (the “Rules”) may be more stringent than current law requires, a reflection of MilkPEP’s long-standing commitment to promote honest, truthful communications with its users. In addition, these Rules are not intended to be a substitute for getting Legal, IT or Communications approval for promotional activities on a social media platform. This is merely a place to start when considering social media as a promotional tool. Curated content is discovered, gathered, and promoted by the brand in social media (a retweet, share, pin, etc.) – but is clearly not created by the brand itself. In such instances, full credit should be given to the owner. It is the act of selecting content to promote that is relevant to the brand story in some way.

Milk Life and REFUEL user-generated or curated content should be developed with a deliberate focus on the following:

·       Messaging that follows all brand guidelines

·       Content that benefits the objectives of MilkPEP, Milk Life and REFUEL programs

·       Content that is from an original source, and is used with permission of owner whenever possible.

**2.     ** **List of MilkPEP social channels (as of 8/7/13)*:**

**a.      ** **Facebook:**

                             i.   <http://www.facebook.com/Milk>

                           ii.   <http://www.facebook.com/bigotedeleche>

                          iii.   <http://www.facebook.com/GotChocolateMilk>

**b.      ** **Twitter:**

                             i.   <http://twitter.com/MilkLife>

                           ii.   <http://twitter.com/bigotedeleche>

                          iii.   <http://twitter.com/GotChocoMilk>

**c.      ** **YouTube:**

                             i.   <http://youtube.com/MilkMustacheCampaign>

                           ii.   <http://youtube.com/eligeleche>

                          iii.   <http://youtube.com/ChocolateMilkRefuel>

**d.      ** **Pinterest:**  <http://pinterest.com/milk>

**e.      ** **Instagram:**  <http://instagram.com/milklife>

**f.      Google+:** <https://plus.google.com/+Milklife>

*All guiding principles included in this guideline will be applied for any new channels that are created.

**3.     ** **Types of content**

The table below depicts the various scenarios for sharing third-party content on MilkPEP social channels, and the protocol for different channels.

**Type of Content**

| 

**Created by**

| 

**Permission to Share**

| 

**Attributing the Source**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
**Image**

| 

Spokesperson

| 

Permission to use images of our spokespeople or celebrity talent is granted based on the terms agreed upon in any Spokesperson or Talent Agreement contract.

| 

We will credit the source of the image as agreed upon in the contract.  
  
Blogger or other Influencer

| 

Obtain permission to share the image on our social channels, by contacting the blogger on Twitter with a Direct Message or through email communication.

| 

We will give credit by doing the following:

Mention the name of the creator who originally produced the image or blog where the image lives and/or tag the page or handle of the source.

Link to either the original post or when permission has been granted the content published on our aggregate "hub" site or GCM.com.  
  
Fan

| 

In cases where a fan shares an image with Milk Life or REFUEL by posting to our timeline, tweeting at us, or through another social action, we may share the image through our channels.

_*See page 6 for our facebook rules about deleting inappropriate content posted by fans._

| 

We will mention that photo was sourced from fan, and when appropriate, mention their first name and last initial or Twitter handle.  
  
Contest Entrant

| 

When an image is submitted as part of a contest, per the rules of the contest, the image becomes the property of MilkPEP, and may be used on social channels.

| 

We will mention that the image was sourced from a fan, and when appropriate mention their first name and last initial or Twitter handle.  
  
**Video**

| 

Spokesperson

| 

Videos created by our spokespeople may be used on our social properties as agreed upon in the relevant spokesperson contract or partnership contract.

| 

We will credit the source of the video by tagging the appropriate handle or page or naming the video creator/star.  
  
Blogger or other Influencer

| 

Obtain permission to share the video on our social channels, by contacting the blogger on Twitter with a Direct Message or through email communication.

| 

We will give credit by doing the following:

Mention the name of the creator who originally produced the video or blog where the video lives and/or tag the page or handle of the source.

Link to either the original post or when permission has been granted the content published on our aggregate "hub" site or GCM.com.  
  
Fan

| 

In cases where a fan shares a video with Milk Life or REFUEL by posting to our timeline, tweeting at us, or through another social action, we may share that video through our channels

| 

We will mention that the video was sourced from fan, and when appropriate, mention their first name and last initial. We will have the user sign a waiver, giving us permission to post on our channels.  
  
Contest Entrant

| 

When a video is submitted as part of a contest, per the rules of the contest, the video becomes the property of MilkPEP, and may be used on social channels.

| 

We will mention that the video was sourced from a fan, and when appropriate mention their first name and last initial.  
  
**Recipe**

| 

Spokesperson

| 

Recipes created by our spokespeople or brand partners may be used on our social properties as agreed upon in any relevant contracts under which the recipes were created.

| 

When posting the recipe to our social channels we will credit the source within the post copy when specified by a contract.

We will always credit the creator of recipes that come from third-parties on our aggregate "hub" site.  
  
Blogger or other Influencer

| 

Obtain permission to share the recipe on our social channels, by contacting the blogger on Twitter with a Direct Message or through email communication.

| 

We will credit the source of the recipe by tagging the appropriate handle or page or naming the creator.  
  
Fan

| 

In cases where a fan shares a recipe with Milk Life by posting to our timeline, tweeting at us, or through another social action, we may share the recipe through our channels.

| 

We will mention that the recipe was sourced from fan, and when appropriate, mention their first name and last initial.  
  
Contest Entrant

| 

When a recipe is submitted as part of a contest, per the rules of the contest, the recipe becomes the property of MilkPEP, and may be used on social channels.

| 

We will mention that the recipe was sourced from a fan, and when appropriate mention their first name and last initial.  
  
**Blog Post**

|  | 

Obtain permission to share the blog post on our social channels, by contacting the blogger on Twitter with a Direct Message or through email communication.

| 

We will give credit by doing the following:

Mention the name of the creator who originally produced the content or blog where the content lives and/or tag the page or handle of the source.

Link to either the original post or when permission has been granted the content published on our aggregate "hub" site.  
  
**Quote**

|  | 

MilkPEP may feature quotes from third parties in content, so long as the source of the quote is clearly named.

| 

When a quote is used in social content, the source of that quote will be vetted for issues.  
  
**_Sample Communication for obtaining permission to use third-party content:_**

_I came across your  _[A Simple St. Patrick's Day Breakfast](http://www.thoughtfullysimple.com/a-simple-st-patricks-day-breakfast/)  _blog post yesterday and absolutely loved it! I work for the National Milk Life Campaign and wanted to see if we could share your cute idea on our social media channels for St. Patrick’s Day. Would that be OK with you?  _

_We’ll be sure to tag your page/handle and link back to your blog on all posts if you’re ok with us sharing them to our followers. I’ve included a list of our social channels below for your reference:_

_Facebook:  _[Milk Life ](http://www.facebook.com/Milk)

_Twitter:_[@MilkLife](https://twitter.com/MilkLife)

_Instagram:_[@MilkLife](http://instagram.com/milklife)

_Pinterest:  _[Milk](http://pinterest.com/milk)

_Please let me know if you have any questions._

**4.     ** **Content Requirements and Clearances:**

**A.  **Content and Originality: All user-generated content must be the original work of the user, must not include any material subject to a third-party’s copyright or trademark protection, may not have been previously published, and may not have won previous awards.

**B.  **No Names and Likeness Without Permission: Photos must not contain any individual’s name, in whole or in part, refer to public figures, contain materials embodying the names, likenesses, or other identifying elements of any entity and/or person, living or dead, without permission.

**C.  **No Illegal, Offensive or Inappropriate Content: User generated content must not contain words, images or statements considered offensive to individuals of any race, ethnicity, religion, sexual orientation, or socioeconomic group nor contain material that is unlawful, sexually explicit, libelous or content that potentially infringes on third party rights.  Content must be in keeping with MilkPEP’s reputation and image, at Sponsor’s sole discretion.

D.  Child-Created Content:  Content created or submitted by a child under age 13 may not be used on any platform.

**5.     ** **Transparency and Disclosures**

MilkPEP will always disclose when working with a spokesperson and our partners are also expected to disclose when working with us. Our spokespeople allow MilkPEP to use their approved name, likeness and endorsement in connection with the campaign in press materials and content related to the Program from completion through a date agreed upon by both parties.

Transparency and honesty are the essence of social media communications. This means, among other things, that it must be clear that MilkPEP is the sponsor or “owner” of any Facebook page or other social media presence.  In addition, MilkPEP has developed a Social Media and Endorsement Policy to provide guidance to employees, agencies, bloggers, talent, and others who are communicating with consumers via social media on behalf of MilkPEP and its entities.

This Policy requires, among other things, that anyone who speaks on behalf of MilkPEP or its entities for promotional purposes must disclose their relationship with the company and reveal any compensation they may be receiving. For instance, bloggers who are compensated for their participation in an activation, program or event must disclose that we have hired them or paid them for their services. Per the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) Guidelines, the Disclosure must be clear, easy to find and easy to read.  It should appear on the page where milk is being promoted in text sized similarly to other text on the page.  The Policy also requires that all communication be honest and truthful and comply with all laws. 

All agencies, bloggers, contractors and others who will post content or messages about MilkPEP and its entities via any social media platform must agree, in writing, to comply with the Social Media and Endorsement Policy. Please speak to Legal before entering into a relationship with any bloggers who will receive any compensation, so a determination can be made, on a case-by-case basis, about the best way to proceed.

MilkPEP complies with the Federal Trade Commission’s “.com Disclosures – How to Make Effective Disclosures in Digital Advertising.”

**6.     ** **Platform-specific Rules**

**Facebook:  **The rules below are our guidelines for Facebook and are displayed in our “About Me” section

Welcome to [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page] on Facebook (the "Milk Life Page"). We're glad you visited the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page] and invite you to use the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page] to interact with us and fellow [milk / chocolate milk] lovers.

We invite you to share your comments on our posts and to post photos, videos and other content to our Timeline. However, we do ask that you follow these guidelines when posting anything to the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page]:

1\. Play nice and be kind - no bullying, harassing language, threats or trolling. 

2\. Don't post any material that is abusive, defamatory, racist, offensive, obscene, false or illegal. We will remove it.

3\. Don't post (or post links to) spam, good luck/chain posts, commercial/promotional posts, or repeated posts including unconstructive, inflammatory or otherwise objectionable comments/statements.

4\. Don’t post pictures, videos or content that belong to someone else or that include someone else without their permission. 

5\. All of your activity on the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page] must comply with Facebook's Statement of Rights and Responsibilities.

We reserve the right (but have no obligation) to remove what you post from the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page]. If you violate our guidelines more than three times, we will block you from our Page.

All content provided on the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page] is the sole responsibility of the person submitting it. The National Fluid Milk Processor Promotion Board (“MilkPEP”) does not endorse, nor is it responsible for any of the postings, opinions, photographs, video or other submissions on this Facebook page and MilkPEP expressly disclaims any and all liability in connection with User Submissions. You agree through the use of this Facebook page to indemnify MilkPEP for any costs, expenses, losses, damages, or claims arising out of or in connection with your use of this Facebook page.

By posting photographs, video, information or other content to this Facebook page, you automatically grant, and you represent and warrant that you have the right to grant, to MilkPEP and its affiliates, an irrevocable, perpetual, sub-licensable, non-exclusive, transferable, royalty-free, worldwide license to use such content for any purpose in any media, including promotions, to prepare derivative works of, or incorporate into other works, such content, and to grant and authorize sublicenses of the foregoing.

MilkPEP reserves the right, at its sole discretion, to modify the foregoing terms and conditions at any time without further notice.

Thank you for “liking” the [Milk Life Campaign Page / Got Chocolate Milk Page]!

**Twitter:**

**a.      **Retweet Guidelines

MilkPEP may retweet content from third-parties that promotes Milk Life or MilkPEP or REFUEL message, or adds value to our social community.

**b.      **Contest Submissions

When a piece of content is submitted as part of a contest, per the rules of the contest, it becomes the property of MilkPEP, and may be used in future content. When we post user-generated content to our social channels, we will attribute credit to the creator of that content in a manner fit for that platform.

**c.      **Spokesperson Protocol

We must use “Ad” or “Sponsored” or another word that clearly tells consumers the message is from a marketer.

Whatever we use,  _it must appear at the beginning of the tweet_ , not the end.

Multi-tweet approaches are not acceptable because the tweets may not appear in a consumer’s feed consecutively.

When using short links, they must follow the same rules as full length links and be easy to understand.

**Instagram** : 

Guidelines for sharing third-party images on Instagram:

**Source**

| 

**Permission for Sharing**

| 

**Attribution of the Source**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Brand Partner or Spokesperson

| 

Per the contract stipulations, content from a brand partner may be shared on our Instagram feed.

| 

The image caption will give credit to the image creator through a tag or mention of the source, as agreed upon in the contract.  
  
Bloggers, Influencers and Fans

| 

Obtain permission to share the image through email or Twitter Direct Message with the image creator

| 

The image caption will give credit to the image creator through a tag or mention of the source.  
  
Contest Entrant

| 

When an image is submitted as part of a contest, per the rules of the contest, the image becomes the property of MilkPEP, and that image may be shared on our Instagram feed.

| 

When the image is posted, the caption will mention that the image was sourced from fan, and tag their Instagram username or include their first name and last initial when appropriate.  
  
**Pinterest:**

Guidelines for sharing Third-party Content on Pinterest:

**Source**

| 

**Permission for Sharing**

| 

**Attribution of the Source**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Brand Partner or Spokesperson

| 

Per the contract stipulations, content from a brand partner may be shared on our Pinterest page.

| 

Create a shared board, and invite program partners to pin

If the content is pinned by MilkPEP, a caption will give credit to the image creator through a tag of their Pinterest page or mention of the source.  
  
Contest Entrant

| 

Per the rules of a contest, submissions become the property of MilkPEP, and we may pin users submissions to our boards as we see fit.

| 

We will attribute the source by tagging the users Pinterest page or mention the users name in the caption.  
  
**7.      ** **Removal Guidelines**

In situations when third-party content usage rights are limited by a contract or other agreement the following steps will be taken:

**a.      **When the rights to content expire, we will assess removal in the following steps:

1\. Decide whether or not we want to keep the content live after contract terms

2\. IF we do want to keep the content live, determine if we can ask the content provider for an extension without any additional fee (celebrities will generally incur an additional fee)

3\. Reach out to content provider to get written consent via email to continue to keep their content live

                                                    i.         If the content provider agrees, keep content live indefinitely

                                                   ii.         If content provide will not allow this, remove content according to contract term

4\. If we do not or cannot keep content live (content no longer valuable, fee will be incurred), remove content according to contract term

**b.      **When the creator of content requests that the content be removed, we will assess the removal in the following steps:

1\. Decide whether or not we want to keep the content live despite the request

2\. If not, remove the content.

3\. If we would like to keep the content live, discuss options with legal counsel.  If content is not subject to contract, it will likely have to be removed.

**Appendix A**

**MilkPEP Guidelines for Obtaining Rights for Use of Third Party Content**

**_Usage Scenarios:_**

**Different ways MilkPEP uses online influencers**

| 

**_Fee Paid_**

| 

**_Expenses Paid_**

| 

**_Receipt of Goods_**

**_  (Race Bib, Athletic Gear, Links to bloggers website on MilkPEP’s websites, etc)_**

| 

**_Traveling on behalf of MilkPEP_**

| 

**_Legal Guidelines_**

| 

**_Legal Coverage_**  
  
---|---|---|---|---|---|---  
  
**__Media spokesperson:__**  official spokesperson, requiring message and media training

**__Satellite Media Tour:__**  official spokesperson

**__Speaking engagements:__**  medical, nutritional, fitness, blog conferences targeting industry professionals and influencers

**__Embedding bloggers at events:__**

Contracting with bloggers to provide VIP access at events, unveils, etc. and encouraging them to post about their experiences.

**__Fitness event participation:__**  Representing REFUEL at public sporting events

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Ad hoc

| 

Ad hoc

| 

MilkPEP Spokesperson Legal Agreement

| 

-Compensation/Term

-Rights Reserved / Change Orders/Modification

-Indemnification

\- Influencing Government Policy

-Confidentiality

-Relationship of Parties

-Failure to Perform

-Disparagement (2yrs)/Conflict of Interest(term, +30-days)

-Ownership

-Auditing

-Assignability

-Termination

-Applicable Law

-FTC Disclosure Requirements  
  
**__“Unofficial” / ad-hoc media opportunities__**

| 

No

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Travel Waiver

| 

-Use of name/likeness

-Indemnifies/hold harmless PEP/Agency

-FTC Disclosure Requirements  
  
  “           “

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Travel Waiver

| 

-Use of name/likeness

-Indemnifies/hold harmless PEP/Agency

-FTC Disclosure Requirements  
  
“           “

| 

No

| 

No

| 

Yes

| 

No

| 

Race Entry Waiver

| 

-Use of name/likeness

-Indemnifies/hold harmless PEP/Agency

-FTC Disclosure Requirements  
  
**__Earned Media Program support:__**  sharing MilkPEP messages or user-generated content in their channels

| 

No

| 

No

| 

No

| 

No

| 

No

| 

n/a  
  
**__Earned Media Program support ~ Surprise & Delight:__** sharing MilkPEP messages or user-generated content in their channels  non-solicited)

| 

No

| 

No

| 

Yes

_(send a Breakfast @ Home Gift)_

| 

No

| 

No

| 

n/a  
  
**_3 rd Party Owned Media – Distributed through MilkPEP Channels: _**MilkPEP licensing 3rd party editorial content (recipes, image or editorial article/video

| 

No

| 

No

| 

Ad hoc

| 

No

| 

Licensing Agreement

| 

-Perpetual, royalty-free licenses of photos and materials  
  
**__MilkPEP Owned Media – Distributed through MilkPEP or Partnership Channels:__**  Partnering with MilkPEP to create-produce content  (Images, video, quotes/written, links)

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Ad hoc

| 

Ad hoc

| 

MilkPEP Sponsorship Legal Agreement

| 

-Compensation/Term

-Use of Trademarks

-Termination & Survival

-Represents & Warranties

-Rights Reserved / Change Orders/Modification

-Confidentiality

-Indemnification

-Approvals

-Assignability

-Applicable Law/Jurisdiction

-Limited Liability

-Relationship of Parties

-Notices

-Auditing

-Influencing Government Policy

-Equal Opportunity

-Insurance Provision

-Maintenance of Records  
  
**__Twitter party support <or> Blogger Tour__**

Hosting or participating in a Twitter chat/party (i.e. promoting on channels and managing conversation flow and prizing questions)

| 

Yes

| 

Yes

| 

Ad hoc

| 

Ad hoc

| 

MilkPEP

Media Promotion Legal Agreement

| 

-Term, Compensation, Termination

-Confidentiality

-Ownership Rights; Trademarks

-Warranties & Indemnification

-Maintenance of Records

-FTC Disclosure Requirements  
  
**__Contest Winner:__**

Sharing content or MilkPEP messages on their channels or via MilkPEP channels

| 

No

| 

Based on official rules

| 

Based on official rules

| 

No

| 

Official Rules

| 

-Based on terms outlined in official rules

-Winner Affidavit

-Talent Agreement

d  
  
**YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THESE TERMS**  
By using this site, you signify your assent to the Milk Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our site. Your continued use of the Milk site following the posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes. If you have questions or concerns regarding this Web site’s privacy statement, you should first contact:

Milk PEP  
ATTN: Marketing Coordinator, milklife.com  
1250 H Street, NW  
Suite 950  
Washington, DC 20005
